Guide to the George Fisher papers, 1951-1990.
Fisher, George papers, 1951-1990
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George Fisher papers, 1951-1990
7437
George Fisher, 1938-1990
22 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, photographs, drawings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Elysian Fields, Booksellers, business records, 1974-1988, including orders, invoices, bills, mail order forms, special order correspondence. bibliographies and catalogs; also, personal correspondence, a clipping and subject file, photo prints, original erotic and pornographic manuscripts, erotica and pornographic artwork, including drawings and photographs.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
George Alan Fisher, born January 6, 1938, in Los Angeles, worked for a number of airlines in the cargo traffic section, export and import, first in California, then from ca. 1965-1967 in Copenhagen for a Scandanavian airline, SAS, and then for 23 years at JFK airport in New York City for Japan Airlines. He retired in June 1990. Under the name Ed Drucker, he ran Elysian Fields, Booksellers, since its opening in 1972. Elysian Fields specializes in out of print gay, lesbian, and bisexual fiction and non-fiction with some general sexuality books as well. Fisher traveled worldwide. He died October 3, 1990.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The George Fisher Collection consists of personal correspondence, including many letters from his mother, several letters to and from Fisher describing his many travels abroad, and numerous postcards received by Fisher from friends around the world. The records of Elysian Fields include accounts, bills, brochures, advertisements, mail order forms, invoices, orders, dealer orders and queries especially pertaining to special orders and first editions, bibliographies and lists of books and reprints, Elysian Fields catalogs and other book and pornographic catalogs, a clipping file, a small subject file, audiotapes, slides, photoprints, and negatives. The collection also includes erotic and pornographic original manuscripts, and a large collection of original erotic and pornographic artwork, including layouts, drawings, charcoal sketches, photographs, and proofsheets; there is a small amount of correspondence pertaining to the artwork.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Elysian Fields Booksellers.
Subjects:
Antiquarian booksellers--New York (State).; Gay men--Books and reading.; Erotica.; Pornography.; Pedophilia.; Nudism.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence and Personal Material
Boxes 1-2,38
Series II. Elysian Fields Booksellers Orders, Bills, Receipts, Bibliographies
Boxes 3-10,38
Series III. Lists, Catalogs
Boxes 11-13, 41-42
Series IV. Photoprints, Slides, Audiotapes
Boxes 14-15
Series V. Clippings and Subject Files
Boxes 16-18,39
Series VI. Manuscripts
Boxes 19-20
Series VII. Artwork
Boxes 21-37
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence and Personal Material
  - Correspondence and Personal 1957-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1-16)
    Includes correspondence between Fisher and his parents, pertaining to his wide travel in Europe. Fisher's relationship with his mother is particularly documented. There are many postcards from friends throughout the world. There are letters from epistolary correspondents, frequently to Fisher's Provincetown post office box, of an erotic nature (with a specialty of J/O and A/F letters).
  - La Cronica Junior High School yearbooks, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Birth announcement of Brian Richard Voelcker, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Photo- Fisher's Parents? (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Resumes/job applications (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Photo negatives: men at the beach (personal?) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence and Personal 1950's-1989 (Box 2)
    Includes diplomas, legal and tax papers, some correspondence as described in box 1, and Fisher's Japan Airlines file of work related papers.
  - The Poinsettia: Hollywood High School yearbook, 1953 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Democratic convention/1976 election (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - OWL (Older Women's League) information (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Information on Alzheimer's disease/aging (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Erotic cards (mainly seasonal, i.e. Valentine's Day, Christmas, etc.) (Box 38)
- Series II. Elysian Fields Booksellers Orders, Bills, Receipts, Bibliographies and Booklists
  - 1974-1976 (Box 3)
  - 1976-1978 (Box 4)
  - 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 6)
  - 1982-1984 (Box 7)
  - 1984, 1987-1988 (Box 8)
    Includes dealers correspondence, first editions, quotes, and some straight sexuality and non-sexuality books.
  - 1969-1988 (Box 9)
    Special orders, tax papers, consultant fees, dealers correspondence.
  - 1966-1989 (Box 10)
    Bibliographies, special orders, dealers correspondence, university library orders.
  - Clippings: mainly book reviews (Box 38, Folder 5-10)
  - Miscellaneous clippings/information (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Typed book reviews/summaries (by Fisher?) (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Gay Academic Union materials (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Dealer correspondence (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters/flyers/catalogs (Box 38, Folder 15-17)
  - Cliipings: book reviews (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: St. Martin's Press, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - American Book Review, Double focus on AIDS and Women in Power, 1990:May/June (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - The New York Review of Books, 12/9/76 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Antiquarian Book Monthly Review, 1989:July (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Information on Christ and the Homosexual by Robert Wood (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Author correspondence (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Simoneau, Chantale (Box 38, Folder 25)
- Series III. Lists and Catalogs
  - Catalogs, 1974-1990 (Box 11-13, 41-42)
    Catalogs, brochures, advertisements, fliers, lists, and mail solicitations of an erotic or pornographic nature; also, Elysian Fields catalogs, and a small number of straight sexuality catalogs and non-erotic book catalogs.
- Series IV. Photoprints, Slides, Audiotapes
  - Visual Material (Box 14)
    George Fisher Travel Slides ca. 1950's-1960's, strips of gay films, n.d.
  - Visual Material (Box 15)
    George Fisher Travel Slides c. 1950's-1960's, erotic and pornographic photographs, including ca. Victorian era, famous personalities, stylized motif, and physique
- Series V. Clippings and Subject File
  - Clippings and Subject Files ca. 1960-1989 (Box 16)
    Includes various topics, sexual and non-sexual.
  - Subject File (Box 17)
    Includes legal briefs, and small books of poetry and other prose.
  - Clippings and Subject File (Box 18, Folder 1-9)
    Includes Legal briefs.
  - Becoming a People...a 4,000 year gay and lesbian chronology by Jim Kepner (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Informational flyer on "A Black and White Ball", NYC, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - London Arrest Scrapbook (contains numerous clippings) (Box 39)
- Series VI. Manuscripts
  - Manuscripts (Box 19)
    Typescript prose fictions (pornographic), gay and heterosexual, including a manuscript by James John Proferes.
- Series VII. Artwork
  - Artwork (Box 21-35)
    Erotic and pornographic drawings, charcoal sketches, photographs, layouts, dustjackets, proofsheets; a large number of sexual motifs are represented; includes a small amount of correspondence pertaining to the artwork.
  - Artwork and correspondence, 1962-1967 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    Guild Press ( Fizeek Art Quarterly), DC, and Media Arts, NYC. Artists: Martin Parent, "Zip", Michael Priggins, Robin
  - Artwork and correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    Guild Press, artists: Pat, Jox, Steve Masters, John Matthews
  - Artwork and correspondence, 1962-1966 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    Guild Press, artists David Mills, George Miller, Nerol
  - Artwork and correspondence, Guild Press, 1963 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - William M. Maclane Studios artwork (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - William M. Maclane Studios artwork (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Etienne artwork (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Artwork and correspondence, 1962-1965 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    Guild Press, artists Ralph Smith, Lawrence Smith, Larry Tippin, CT
  - Artwork and correspondence, 1962-1968 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    Guild Press, artists Robert Payne, "Zip", Martin Parent
  - Grecian Guild Pictorial clipping, April 1962 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Layout materials (Box 37)
    Layout material for various publications on various themes, including heterosexuality, lesbianism, gay male sexuality, phallic development, and sadomasochism.